<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"><title type="text">The Verge</title><subtitle type="text">The Verge is about technology and how it makes us feel. Founded in 2011, we offer our audience everything from breaking news to reviews to award-winning features and investigations, on our site, in video, and in podcasts.</subtitle><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com" /><id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/index.xml</id><entry><title>What happens when AI comes for our fonts?</title><link href="https://www.theverge.com/ai-artificial-intelligence/688637/typography-fonts-ai" /><id>https://www.theverge.com/ai-artificial-intelligence/688637/typography-fonts-ai</id><updated>2025-06-20T08:27:03-04:00</updated><summary type="html">Monotype is keen for you to know what AI might do in typography. As one of the largest type design companies in the world, Monotype owns Helvetica, Futura, and Gill Sans - among 250,000 other fonts. In the typography giant's 2025 Re:Vision trends report, published in February, Monotype devotes an entire chapter to how AI [&amp;#8230;]</summary></entry><entry><title>The Verge’s guide to Amazon Prime Day 2025</title><link href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/689359/amazon-prime-day-tech-deals-guide-2025" /><id>https://www.theverge.com/tech/689359/amazon-prime-day-tech-deals-guide-2025</id><updated>2025-06-20T19:07:11-04:00</updated><summary type="html">Amazon’s mega sale is nearly upon us. This year, Prime Day will kick off on July 8th and run through July 11th, which, for those counting, is twice as long as previous years. Most everything else will likely be the same — well, aside from Amazon’s so-called “Today&amp;#8217;s Big Deals&amp;#8221; feature — making it a [&amp;#8230;]</summary></entry><entry><title>The Nintendo Switch 2 is an awesome upgrade for parents like me</title><link href="https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/690224/nintendo-switch-2-parenting-gameshare" /><id>https://www.theverge.com/nintendo/690224/nintendo-switch-2-parenting-gameshare</id><updated>2025-06-20T19:37:32-04:00</updated><summary type="html">I wouldn't have preordered a Nintendo Switch 2 just for myself. The price is high, there's no new Smash Bros. or Metroid Prime (yet), and I've got a perfectly good original Nintendo Switch and Steam Deck that keep me plenty busy. At first, I could only justify the $450 because I write about gaming tech [&amp;#8230;]</summary></entry><entry><title>Inside the courthouse reshaping the future of the internet</title><link href="https://www.theverge.com/policy/690440/e-barrett-prettyman-courthouse-dc-district-meta-google-antitrust-doge" /><id>https://www.theverge.com/policy/690440/e-barrett-prettyman-courthouse-dc-district-meta-google-antitrust-doge</id><updated>2025-06-20T15:24:50-04:00</updated><summary type="html">The future of the internet will be determined in one building in Washington, DC - and for six weeks, I watched it unfold. For much of this spring, the E. Barrett Prettyman Courthouse in downtown Washington, DC, was buzzing with lawyers, reporters, and interested onlookers jostling between dimly lit courtrooms that hosted everyone from the [&amp;#8230;]</summary></entry></feed>