<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0" xml:lang="en-US">
<script/>
<title type="text">The Verge</title>
<subtitle type="text">The Verge is about technology and how it makes us feel. Founded in 2011, we offer our audience everything from breaking news to reviews to award-winning features and investigations, on our site, in video, and in podcasts.</subtitle>
<updated>2025-06-21T16:02:03+00:00</updated>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com"/>
<id>https://www.theverge.com/rss/index.xml</id>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.theverge.com/rss/index.xml"/>
<icon>https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/01/verge-rss-large_80b47e.png?w=150&h=150&crop=1</icon>
<entry>
<author>
<name>Andru Marino</name>
</author>
<author>
<name>Barbara Krasnoff</name>
</author>
<title type="html">
<![CDATA[ Weird-shaped notebooks make me want to write again  ]]>
</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theverge.com/tech/690335/notebook-triangle-sidekick-favorite"/>
<id>https://www.theverge.com/?p=690335</id>
<updated>2025-06-20T13:09:19-04:00</updated>
<published>2025-06-22T10:00:00-04:00</published>
<category scheme="https://www.theverge.com" term="Tech"/>
<category scheme="https://www.theverge.com" term="Verge Favorites"/>
<summary type="html">
<![CDATA[ Andru Marino is an audio and video producer at The Verge. “I make videos on our YouTube / TikTok / Instagram channels, and have produced our podcasts like Vergecast, Decoder, and Why’d You Push That Button?” He also keeps a lot of notes, and his latest favorite places to keep them are the Triangle and [&#8230;] ]]>
</summary>
<content type="html">
<![CDATA[ <figure> <img alt="White keyboard with L-shaped notebook wrapped around it. the notebook is filled with doodles." data-caption="" data-portal-copyright="" data-has-syndication-rights="1" src="https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/06/Sidekick-notebook_AMarino.jpg?quality=90&#038;strip=all&#038;crop=0,0,100,100" /> <figcaption> </figcaption> </figure> <p class="has-text-align-none"><em>Andru Marino is an audio and video producer at </em>The Verge<em>. “I make videos on our YouTube / TikTok / Instagram channels, and have produced our podcasts like </em>Vergecast<em>,</em> Decoder<em>, and </em>Why’d You Push That Button?<em>” He also keeps a lot of notes, and his latest favorite places to keep them are the Triangle and Sidekick notebooks. I asked him about them.</em></p> <p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Where did you first hear about these notebooks?</strong></p> <p class="has-text-align-none">I don’t really remember when I first saw the Triangle Notebook. It was probably an Instagram ad. I had kept a link to the notebook’s website in a browser tab on my phone for a few months and kept thinking about it.&nbsp;</p> <p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>When did you buy it, and what went into the decision?</strong></p> <p class="has-text-align-none">I bought it in April, and what really attracted me was how weird it was. Why does the notebook need to be a triangle? Oh, it opens up into a square! Wow, I love that! The main reason I use paper is to doodle, and I thought this shape would inspire me to doodle differently.&nbsp;</p> <p class="has-text-align-none">And then I saw this company also made another notebook called the Sidekick that basically looks like an L when opened, so it is angled alongside your computer keyboard. That was <em>so</em> wacky to me. So I bought that one too. </p> <p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>What do you like about them?</strong></p> <p class="has-text-align-none">This seems more like an art experiment than anything. I love objects that make you rethink how they are used. I typically have Post-it notes or a spiral notebook on my desk so I can write something down or doodle during a meeting. The Sidekick doesn’t take up a ton of space on my desk either opened or closed.&nbsp;</p> <p class="has-text-align-none">The Triangle Notebook is actually great for using on your lap or other unconventional surfaces, as it is pretty sturdy and lays flat on its spine.&nbsp;</p> <p class="has-text-align-none">Both notebooks also encourage me to use my handwriting more, which was a New Year’s resolution I had.&nbsp;</p> <div class="embed-embed"><a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/2521/7878/files/TriangleNotebook_action_TanMavitan_480x480.gif?v=1590007573" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">View Link</a></div> <p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Is there anything about them that you dislike, or that you think could be improved?</strong></p> <p class="has-text-align-none">I am not entirely sure if it makes sense to take notes on an L-shaped piece of paper, but that is just what makes the Sidekick different.&nbsp;</p> <p class="has-text-align-none">The Triangle Notebook could have a few more pages in it. It is nicely bound and sort of expensive ($33), so I would like to get more use out of it. Also it is so long! I don’t know where to store it.&nbsp;</p> <p class="has-text-align-none">And the pages don’t tear out very easily. I’d love to give someone a note on a weird-shaped piece of paper.&nbsp;</p> <p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>Who would you recommend it to?</strong></p> <p class="has-text-align-none">I’d recommend the Sidekick to an artist who wants to doodle during meetings — which is why I bought this. But I can also see it working for someone who draws on a tablet and wants to briefly write down some notes about what they are working on.&nbsp;</p> <p class="has-text-align-none">I don’t know who I would recommend the Triangle Notebook to besides someone who likes weird objects. I’d love to know if someone feels like they do their best work on a triangle-shaped notebook. </p> <p class="has-text-align-none"><strong>You started this by saying you hoped these notebooks would inspire you to doodle differently. Have they?</strong></p> <p class="has-text-align-none">So far, no. My notes look the same mess as ever, but it has encouraged me to doodle more <em>and</em> write more, so that makes me happy.&nbsp;</p> ]]>
</content>
</entry>
</feed>
